let's look at our instruction scheduling
quiz solution as is this takes one cycle
to do the load if the load latency was
one cycle then the ad could happen the
next cycle but because the load takes
two cycles the add can only happen in
cycle three so we have one cycle three
the ad takes only one cycle so the store
can proceed then we can do the load it
doesn't depend on anything so we can do
the load index cycle five the ad however
can now happen only in cycle seven and
finally the store happens in cycle eight
so as is this executes in eight cycles
the question is now can we schedule this
better to avoid some of these stalls and
we had a stall here and here to avoid a
stall here we need to place between the
load and the add an instruction that can
be done here without violating
dependencies we can see that this load
here
doesn't depend on any of the previous
three instructions except that we will
destroy r1 if we move that instruction
here so the correct solution to this is
we will move the load there but we will
rename
rr1 into something else so the program
becomes now
load word r1
0 of r2 as before
now we move the other load there put the
result in some r10 let's say
now we can do this add because in the
third cycle we can do it
now that we have done this add we can
actually do this the load has already
happened
we are now in the second cycle since
then so the second add can happen
the add was using r1 now we have to use
r10
next we will do our store and the last
remaining store
as you can see
now we have a processor where
whenever we need two cycles for the load
there is something in between the load
and the use of its result here r1 is
loaded we then don't use r1 and then we
add to it
and here r10 is loaded and then we don't
do anything with r10 and then we add to
it
so this can be done in six cycles
eliminating both of the stall cycles
that we previously had